

CONTACT



96784335



aqifsariman@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/aqif-sariman-20b869160/



Singapore

EXPERTISE SKILLS

ReactJS

NodeJS

ExpressJS

нтмі

CSS

PostgreSQL

Bootstrap

Rest API

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Javascript

Python

AQIF SARIMAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ABOUT ME

I am a highly motivated individual with immense interest in statistics and data mining. Inquisitive in nature, I often find myself identifying gaps in work processes to come up with a feasible solution that benefits all parties. I want to succeed in a stimulating and challenging environment, building the success of the company while I experience advancement opportunities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2018-Current

Air Traffic Controller

- Ensure safe, orderly and expeditious movements of aircraft from ground to air.
- Safety Officer in the team to deliver safety briefings and ensure the team follows the rules and guidelines accordingly.

2016-2018

Supply Assistant Comms in Singapore Armed Forces

- Maintain all radio and night vision equipment to its pristine condition for outfiled use.
- Handing/Taking over of equipment from different parties smoothly.

EDUCATION

2021-2022

Rocket Academy

Full-stack Web Development

- Build full-stack projects using all the stacks listed which includes handling backend data using Sequelize.
- Clean code and file organization for pushing to GitHub.
- Able to deploy to Github, Heroku and Firebase.
- Used multiple APIs for projects such as Google Maps API, Weather API etc.

2013-2016

Singapore Polytechnic
Diploma in Mechanical Engineering

- Vice-President School of Mechanical Engineering
- Main Committee as Sports Rep in School of Mechanical Engineering



CONTACT



96784335



aqifsariman@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/aqif-sariman-20b869160/



Singapore

EXPERTISE SKILLS

ReactJS

NodeJS

ExpressJS

HTML

CSS

PostgreSQL

Bootstrap

Rest API

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Javascript

Python

AQIF SARIMAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROJECTS

In a span of 1 year, I have worked on multiple projects to showcase my ability as a Software Engineer. Stacks that were mainly used are ReactJS, ExpressJS, REST APIs, doing coding challenges in Python and handling PostgreSQL using Sequelize, all while ensuring that the UI/UX experience and security for authorization is kept at its highest priority.

Jul 2022

EV Charging APP

- Full stack app using ReactJS, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL with Sequelize, HTML and pure CSS
- Google Map API used for the navigation of the user to the point of interest
- Signup and login authorization was set up using JsSHA
- Users are able to add funds to their wallet for future EV Charging activities
- Similar to past projects, all server are run by ExpressJS
- Deployed to Heroku

Jun 2022

Word Play Game

- Full stack app using ExpressJS, PostgreSQL with Sequelize, HTML and pure CSS
- Hangman-type game for users to guess the correct TV character after picking their favorite TV Show
- ChartsJS was used to display stats of user i.e. winning rate, losing rate and games played
- Deployed to Heroku

April 2022

Travel Planner APP

- Server side app using ExpressJS, PostgreSQL, HTML and bootstrap
- Weather API was used for the weather forecast for the city that is chosen
- Signup and login authorization was set up using JsSHA
- DOM Manipulation used for the effects on the website
- Deployed to Heroku and AWS EC2 was used for the DB

Jan 2022

Video Poker Game

- Popular casino game made using Javascript, HTML and CSS
- DOM manipulation used for the cards on screen
- Other than the main rules of the game, 7-Card Stud rule also included in the game
- · Font-end work for this project
- Deployed to github.io